Irisviel...
アイリスフィール
Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界の為に
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
紅く汚された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
見失ったか
I've lost sight of them.
If I can't see them, I'll sense them.
姿が見えないのなら 気配を感じ取る
戦車
A chariot?
I've got you, Rider!
捕らえたぞ ライダー
Rider, look.
ライダー あい あれ
She's following us, isn't she?
僕らのこと追ってきてないか
誰かと思えばセイバーか
Well, if it isn't Saber.
Saves us the trouble of looking for her.
こりゃ探す手間が省けたわ
Wait.
つうか なあ坊主 オートバイという乗り物はあんなにも速いものなのか
Hey, boy, are motorcycles usually that fast?
That's a motorcycle?
バイク あれが
いや いや いや そんな無茶な
No, that's impossible.
But with Saber's Riding skill...
でもセイバーの騎乗スキルっと考えれば有り得るのかなあ
I suppose it's possible.
Interesting.
面白いわ
そういうことなら余の方も 相応の趣向で臨んでやらんとなあ
In that case, I'll have to play along with her.
We're going down?!
降りるのかよ
Change of plans.
気が変わった あの小娘とは尋常に「車輪」で勝負を決めてやる
I shall use a race to settle things with the girl.
Fine, but take it seriously, okay?
いいけど 慎重にやれよな お前
Don't worry.
案ずるな 天にも地にも我が疾走を阻むものはない
Nothing in Heaven or on Earth can stop me!
This is bad...
まずい マシンの限界が近づいている
I'm reaching the machine's limits.
At this rate...
このままでは
I'm so close, too.
もう少しというところで
Invisible Air!
風王結界
嘘だろ
No way...
She's closing the gap!
距離を詰められてる このままじゃ追いつかれるぞ
She's going to catch up to us!
ただの機械仕掛けを以てしてその走り 見事なり
How impressive for a mechanical contraption to go that fast.
だが あいにくとこちらは戦車でな お行儀良く駆け比べとはいかんぞ
However, this is a chariot!
I'm not going to simply play by the rules.
This is what it means to eat my dust, Saber!
余の「後塵を拝する」とはこういうことだ セイバー
Excellent!
上等 それでこそ誉れも貴き騎士の王
You really are the renowned King of Knights!
Truly the flower of the battlefield!
まっこと貴様は戦場の華よな
Don't underestimate me, King of Conquerors!
侮るなよ 征服王
Rider!
ライダー
覚悟
Prepare yourself!
Irisviel isn't here?
アイリスフィールがいない
No...
そんな
あれは確かにライダーだったはず
That was definitely Rider.
Then where could Irisviel be?
ならば アイリスフィールはどこに
You thought you could fool me with your Servant masquerade?
サーヴァントの偽装をして騙せるとでも思ったか
ライダーのマスターにはそこを看破するだけの諜報能力などない
Rider's Master isn't capable of gathering the necessary intel to find that place.
遠坂は今仕掛けられる状況ではない
Tohsaka is in no position to attack.
By process of elimination, only the Matous could have kidnapped Irisviel.
消去法でいけば
アイリスフィールを連れ去ったのは間桐しか考えられない
答えろ
Answer me.
Where is Irisviel?
アイリスフィールはどこだ
N-No idea!
し し知らない
I have no idea!
俺は何も知らない
Where is Matou Kariya, then?
では 間桐雁夜はどこにいる
Kariya?
雁夜だと
あんな馬鹿野郎の居どころなんぞ
Who knows where that fool is...
I don't know!
知らない ホントに何も知らない
I really don't know anything!
He left this morning with some guy
who said he was a judge from the Church!
教会の監督役とかいう奴と一緒に 朝からどっか行っちまった
A judge?
監督役だと
Kotomine Kirei...
言峰綺礼
I did not expect the real Rider to appear.
よもや 本物のライダーが現れるとはな
実に好都合な展開だ
How very convenient for us.
Luck certainly favors you on the battlefield, doesn't it?
君は戦場において常に幸運を味方につけるな
Matou Kariya.
間桐雁夜
Priest, was this little deception really
worth the use of two Command Spells?
神父 こんな小細工に本当に令呪を二つも費やすだけの意味が
Do not worry, Kariya.
案ずる必要はない 雁夜
さあ 手を出したまえ
Hold out your hand.
私に協力する限り 君は惜しむことなく令呪を消費して構わない
As long as you work with me, you may use
your Command Spells to your heart's desire.
Still...
それにしても 変身能力とは
That transformation ability...
It's a shame he's of the Berserker class
with such an excellent Noble Phantasm.
つくづく バーサーカーのクラスには惜しい宝具を持っている
He's a Heroic Spirit with many stories telling of the
deeds he accomplished under someone else's name.
もともとこいつは
他人を装って武勇を立てた逸話を幾つも持ってる英霊だからな
So this is the best result even with the Command Spell's control?
令呪で強制してやっとこれか
Your Servant's obsession with Saber is incredible.
君のサーヴァントのセイバーに対する執念には恐れ入るな
That's enough.
もういい 消えろ バーサーカー
Disappear, Berserker.
This woman...
この女 こいつが本当に「聖杯の器」なのか
Is she really the Grail vessel?
Her contents are, to be precise.
正しくは「中身」が だがな
心配するな 雁夜
Don't worry, Kariya.
聖杯は必ず君に譲り渡す
I'll let you have the Grail.
それ以前にもう一つ あんたは俺に約束したはずだ 神父
But before that, there's the other promise you made to me, priest.
ああ その件か 問題ないとも
Oh, that?
Everything is arranged.
今夜零時に教会を訪れるがいい
Come to the church tonight, at midnight.
そこで遠坂時臣と対面できる
You will find Tohsaka Tokiomi there.
Don't forget, Kariya.
忘れるなよ 雁夜
Tonight, at midnight.
今夜零時だ それで君の悲願は成就する
Your wish will be fulfilled then.
さて
Now...
We're alone.
人払いは済んだぞ
I don't know who you are, but show yourself.
何者か知らんが そろそろ顔を見せたらどうだ
So, you sensed me.
気付いておったか さすがは歴戦の代行者よ
You are indeed a veteran Executor.
Matou Zouken?
間桐 臓硯か
Correct.
左様
Hey, Rider...
おい ライダー
まさかここから仕掛けるつもりか
Are we really going to attack from here?
From this range?
この間合いから 真っ直ぐに
Straight ahead?
There's a delay before she can activate the sword of light we saw at the river.
奴が河で見せた光の剣は
発動させるまで隙ができる
そこを狙う
We'll strike then.
何でお前 そんな無茶を
Why resort to something so crazy?
無茶だからこそ さ
Because it's crazy.
If she loses even after all this, her defeat will be absolute, without a doubt.
ここまで拮抗した状況で負ければ それこそ紛れもない「完敗」だ
あやつとて改めて余の麾下に加わる気になるかもしれん
She might even decide to join my troops.
You'd go that far?
お前 そうまでして
On the battlefield, she is certainly a star.
戦場において あれは間違いなく地上の星だ
But it is only after she has joined
my army that she can truly shine.
余の軍勢に加えてこそ本当の輝きを放つというものだ
He was never interested in his opponent's power or wealth.
こいつは相手の権威だとか財宝だとかはなから求めてないんだ
Without destroying or degrading them, he sought to conquer their souls.
滅ぼすことなく 貶めることなく 魂そのものを制覇する
That's why he is the King of Conquerors.
故に 征服王
Very well, Rider.
やれよ ライダー お前のやり方で勝てばいい
Win it your way.
坊主 貴様もいよいよ「覇」の何たるかを弁えてきたようだな
Boy, it seems you're finally beginning to understand conquest.
Glory lies beyond the horizon!
彼方にこそ栄え在り
Let us go...
いざ 征かん
Via Expugnatio!
遥かなる蹂躙制覇
Wind!
風よ
Excalibur!
約束された
勝利の剣
What do you want, Matou Zouken?
用件は何だ 間桐臓硯
そうさのう
Well...
I was awfully interested in seeing what clever trick you'd use to break Kariya.
おぬしはどういう手練手管で雁夜めを壊すのか
儂にも興味が尽きぬでなあ
You'd let the Matous' chance of victory disappear?
間桐の勝機をみすみす潰すというのか
雁夜めが悶え苦しむ様は本当に
Watching Kariya suffer in anguish...
見ていて飽きんでな
...is something I'll never tire of.
間桐の勝利か 雁夜の無様な末路か
Victory for the Matous, or a miserable end for him?
I can't choose.
迷い処よ
You enjoy watching your own kin suffer like that?
貴様は肉親の苦悩がそこまで見ていて楽しいか
むしろおぬしは分かってくれるものと思ったのじゃが
And I was thinking you'd understand.
What?
何
You have the same smell as I do.
おぬしからは儂と同類の匂いがするぞ
That of a crawling maggot, attracted by the aroma of Kariya's rotting meat.
雁夜という腐肉の旨味に釣られて這い寄ってきた
蛆虫の匂いがな
Oh, scary, scary.
おお 怖い怖い
青いとはいえ教会の狗
Green or not, you are a dog of the Church.
Simply teasing you endangers me.
からかうとなれば命懸けか
またいずれ見えようぞ 若造
We'll meet again, young one.
By then, see that your true nature
has ripened enough to rival my own.
次に会う時までには
儂と五分に渡り合えるよう
己の本性を充分に肥え太らせておくがいい
Rider...
ライダー
Sorry, boy.
すまんな 坊主 しくじっちまった
I have failed.
Rider!
ライダー 「王の軍勢」を
Use Ionian Hetairoi!
The chariot is all I'm willing to expend on Saber.
セイバーに使うのは「戦車」までだ
But still...
そんなこと言ったって
行っちゃった
She's gone.
A motorcycle, huh?
バイクか
ふむ あれは良いものだ
A magnificent vehicle.
Hey!
お前 勝負に負けた後の第一声がそれか
Those are your first words after losing?
Hey, Rider.
なあ ライダー
How do we get back to town?
僕ら どうやって街まで帰るんだ
そりゃあ まあ 歩くしかないわな
Well...
We'll have to walk.
I guess you're right.
そうだよな
How many more days do I have?
あと何日生きていられるか
How many more times can I fight?
あと何回戦えるのか
But I'm not done yet.
だが 今はまだだ
I'm not...
まだ
Tohsaka Tokiomi!
遠坂 時臣
俺を殺した気でいたか 時臣
So you think you've killed me, Tokiomi?!
In your dreams.
だが 甘かったな
Until I've made you pay,
貴様に報いを与えるまで 俺は何度でも
I'll keep coming back...
Tohsaka...
遠坂
What?
何
Kariya-kun?
雁夜君
Aoi-san?
葵さん
No! It wasn't me!
違う 俺じゃない
これは
This was...
Are you satisfied, Kariya-kun?
満足してる 雁夜君
Now the Matous are sure to win the Holy Grail.
これで聖杯は間桐の手に渡ったも同然ね
俺は
I...
俺
Why?
どうしてよ
私から桜を奪っただけじゃ 物足りないの
Was taking Sakura from me not enough?
Of all the things you could've done, you killed him in front of me?
よりにもよって この人を私の目の前で殺すなんて
どうして
Why?
He...!
そいつが そいつのせいで
It's his fault!
If it weren't for him, no one would need to suffer!
その男さえいなければ 誰も不幸にならずに済んだ
You... and Sakura-chan...
葵さんだって 桜ちゃんだって
All of you could've been happy!
幸せになれたはず
Shut the hell up!
ふざけないでよ
You don't understand a thing about any of this!
あんたなんかに 何が分かるっていうのよ
あんた あんたなんか
You've never even...
...loved anyone!
誰かを好きになったことさえないくせに
There was someone I loved.
好きな人がいた
She was warm and kind...
暖かくて 優しくて 誰よりも幸せになってほしくて
I wanted her to be happier than anyone else.
I would throw away my life for you.
貴女の為なら 命さえ惜しくない
That's why I've endured this pain until now.
そう思ったから 今日まで痛みにも耐えて
耐えて
Endured...
耐えて耐えて耐えて耐えて耐えて耐えて耐えて耐えてきたのだから
Endured, endured, endured, endured, endured, endured, endured...
Endured it all!
I'll never forgive you if you deny all that!
否定されていいわけが 許せるわけがない
嘘だ嘘だ嘘だ
A lie, a lie, a lie!
I do have someone I love...
俺には間違いなく好きな人が 間違いなく確かに俺にはいるんだから
I definitely have someone I love!
俺は何の為に 誰のせいで
What did I do this for?
Whose fault is it?!
If I'm going to die, then I might as well...!
死ぬぐらいなら いっそ
That was a terrible piece of cheap drama,
くだらぬ三文劇であったが
まあ 初めて書いた台本にしては悪くない
but not so bad for your first playwriting attempt.
どうだ綺礼 感想は
Well, Kirei?
What are your thoughts?
The taste of this wine...
酒の味というやつは 思いの他 化けるものだ
It's different from what I remember.
どうやらお前も 見識を広めることの意味を理解しはじめたようだな
I see you've begun to understand what
it means to expand your horizons, then.
If it means the wine will taste this wonderful...
これほど美味と感じる酒ならば
...I would dearly love to sample it again.
ぜひまた
飲んでみたいものだ
Episode 21
Knight on Two Wheels
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
By my Command Spell, I order you.
令呪を以て命ずる
Open your eyes and watch to the end!
刮目して見届けよ
I won't be holding back tonight.
今宵のオレは手加減抜きでいく
I'll just quickly eliminate him.
速やかに排除するのみ
How do he and I differ?
私とやつとがどう違う
If he isn't lost, then what is he?!
迷い人でなくて何なのだ
If I'm in here, who am I?
ここにいる私は 誰
Next Episode
All the World's Evil